what like are we all just idiots and
Robert MD is like the [__] like
[Music]
alrighty so today we are debuting an
episode that we've recorded when did we
record that in like January early
January yeah one of our first episodes I
think it was supposed to be episode two
so yeah it was yeah oh so so oh man this
might be a little cringe then we'll see
it's okay just here just bear with us
through it okay it'll it'll be better I
promise but it is cool because we do
drop a tool um I'm dropping the rebind
multi-a tool which I've had pending
since we've recorded this episode and
I've been wanting to release it
um so that'll get released today and
then
um yeah we just talk a little bit about
blind ssrf's as well I'm not blindness
to surrounds headless ssrfs
um and yeah so should be a pretty good
episode uh forgive the audio quality and
unrefined speech patterns which you know
I like to think have been resolved now
yeah no that was that was way bad we
didn't even have nice mics we didn't
have I didn't have a dynamic mic then
we're just like let's let's record this
thing so yeah but all right before we
jump into that let's talk a little bit
about um we had some news that we wanted
to cover this from this week from this
past week or so
um and yeah Joe what you got yeah so um
trouble security they're back every
episode man every episode hopefully
hopefully this is the last of the drama
it's not really drama it's essentially
resolution to the drama so yeah this
actually happened like literally this
was I think this video came out the day
that we recorded our last episode so we
didn't quite get to sneak it in there
um but essentially trouble security for
those who don't know there was a little
bit of drama that had went on that that
had gone on they took over xss hunter
from mandatory
and they released their own version of
it that was new and improved all this
kind of stuff they
announced that there was some really
interesting stats that they were seeing
some metrics from people who were
actually using it and that raised a lot
of red flags within people from the
community being like oh why are you
looking at our data why are you looking
at these metrics are you you know how
are you knowing all this stuff are you
looking at our payloads are you looking
where it's popping all that kind of
stuff the tldr is that no they weren't
um technically that was always possible
with xss Hunter even the version for
mandatory
um the travel security did a talk at
Defcon I think Defcon 28 so uh maybe a
year a year or two ago
that was basically discussing all of the
current problems with exercise xss
Hunter and all that kind of stuff
um and essentially
because of the backlash from the
community relating to these metrics that
they released which were anonymized um
when they were pulling these metrics to
begin with however because of the
backlash they sat down and they added
end-to-end encryption they they were
like okay this is this is something that
we need to do this is something that we
know has been an issue let's just this
is this is the the flame that ignites
the the flame under our butt right yeah
dude I love the video because he's like
all right bumping that to the top of the
to-do list you know yeah he just like
shows a clue he's just like schedules
out like 10 days and just like sits down
and does it oh my gosh yeah no it's it's
sad though too because like like you
said it was originally possible even
from the very beginning
um you know with the other xss Hunter
and you know mandatory is a good guy but
you know they've it's always been there
the capability has always been there so
and it's open source so it's not like
you don't know that
um yeah so yeah a little bit of an
overreaction there I think from the
community but I'm glad to see that it
spurred the end-to-end encryption
feature implementation that definitely a
win yeah 100 so now all you have to do
just go on xss Hunter and you can put a
pgp key in there and any payload that
pops it's going to automatically use
that key to encrypt the data that gets
sent back and then only you can decrypt
it with your pgp key so nice it's a
great solution
um and it's nice to see them rapidly
addressing those concerns from the
community and as always if you still
aren't sure about it you aren't feeling
great it's totally open source around
yourself go for it like you know
I I wonder if if um you know any of
those big providers that have explicitly
banned it I wonder if they're going to
roll back on that if you are using pgp
encryption or whether that's you're
still going to lose your Bounty yeah
that's true I hope it's not like
permanent damage so to speak yeah
because I know there was like some
immediate backlash and and we mentioned
that we both saw a couple programs send
out
um send out messages to hackers and be
like hey if you're using exercise Hunter
it needs to be a self-hosted version we
don't want it going through you know a
centralized version which is kind of a
weird stance to take because they didn't
have that stance all the while that
exercise Hunter was under mandatory but
whatever but yeah okay well hopefully
hopefully that yeah hopefully that gets
gets fixed it would be nice it's very
convenient it's a very convenient tool
you know for all of that I I've got I
don't have an XS Hunter instance set up
I've got a like little slack ping
callback thing that I use for some of
these things but uh it would definitely
be nice to be able to use those version
yeah 100 and and now that the encryption
is there I think I'll just keep using
the hosted version yeah same yeah cool
um let's see uh you want to talk about
the hacker One World Cup real quick oh
yeah okay so
um hacker one announced on Twitter I
want to say last week that uh the hacker
won World Cup is coming up here soon
um and in order to participate in that
if you're interested in that that is a
well just to give a little context that
is a hacking competition
um that hacker one holds each year and
uh you get representatives from each com
uh country maybe sometimes multiple
representatives and um you're hacking
together on specific Targets this year
this year it's going to be specific
targets last year it was any Target and
um accruing points and then the winners
of those competitions get a bunch of
awesome perks uh Joel the cat man the
cat I was just gonna I wasn't gonna
address it I I every time I see it it's
it's just I I get distracted
um yeah no uh so definitely check that
out if you're interested and um the way
to do that is I will put a link down in
the description
um
you go to the brand ambassador program
page on hacker one and there will be
there's a list of uh ambassadors Yours
Truly Mr Rhino reader Justin Gardner is
the one for uh Virginia so um if you're
in the east coast feel free to reach out
to me and I'll get you in the right chat
um the we'll be releasing this video on
Thursday
um the second and rosters are due Friday
the 3rd so fill out the form right away
um DM me and I will get back to you as
soon as I possibly can
um and I and yeah hopefully hopefully
we'll have some sign ups for that we've
got we've got a full roster already
um pretty much but I think there's some
talk of splitting out another team so uh
definitely don't let that inhibit you
from from checking it out yeah we're
giving you a lot of run time one day but
yeah one day so get on it right now like
well you probably have been trying to
hype this up on Twitter and retweet it
around and stuff so yeah if this is the
first time you're hearing about it and
something you're interested in doing
make sure to check out the link below or
check one of our twitters I'm sure it's
in there somewhere or just Google like
hacker one brand ambassadors yeah and uh
and it should come up and just reach out
there are uh at least in North America
there's four in the US and four in
Canada and I think each sort of region
has uh at least five or six some of them
have even more so definitely reach out
if that's something you you want to
participate all these people should have
their DMS open too so
yeah yeah for sure um I know I've signed
up I know a bunch of other people uh
that we like to act with have signed up
so us is looking strong this year yes as
a pretty strong team it's pretty stacked
I I know I know that it's like to be
fair though
um for the us like we have a lot of
really strong hackers that I think are
going to be hitting it really hard this
year
um but I think last year it would have
been you know it was a little bit more
skewed towards people that can do wide
Recon because any program was in scope
right
um and so you know you've got your hard
Hitters from from Canada Mr Mr today's
new and then um the other big Recon
hitters so I think it should be I think
we've got a good shot at it this year
from the US
yeah I'm pretty stoked I remember from
the program side I was seeing a ton of
reports last year and I was like what
what is this thing that's going on so
I'm I'm very stoked to get to
participate this year any uh any word on
uh whether your company is going to be
participating in the I don't I mean
nobody's reached out to me so okay all
right so we know one target is not the
not one of the targets that's we're
narrowing it down yeah all right what
else we got here on the dock um yeah
chat gbt apis yeah yeah yeah so this is
something that we we always like to talk
about AI stuff
um Chachi PT's a apis are now out so I
think you probably have seen in some of
the mainstream social media apps uh like
Snapchat and Quizlet and I think Tick
Tock and a bunch of other ones have
already ahead of time they've integrated
with the chat GPT apis to try and
increase user engagement all that kind
of good stuff wow so yeah it's now
available to the public and I'm really
excited to see what this is going to do
um there's always been some
unofficial API clients we'll call them
yeah
that used the chat GPD stuff and made it
possible for you to script chat GPT
stuff before it was really publicly
available
but now it's actually available the
official API is out and uh from what
I've heard it's actually not that
expensive so
if engineering or development is
something that piques your interest go
check out the openai blog and maybe code
up some cool security tools look at this
it's like a fifth of a cent for 1K
tokens wow that's pretty good I don't
know what one I don't know what one
token means if that's like 1K 1000
tokens I think that's one I think that's
one query
for one token
yeah I mean I guess like you know I I at
least I envisioned it like those little
tokens in the arcade like you know you
put it in you play the game sort of vibe
dude that's awesome that would be pretty
that'd be pretty sick if it was that
cheap that would be amazing yeah yeah
that's awesome it's really great to see
them finally polish out the product to a
point where they're ready to release it
to the public for you know like official
use I think we're we're about to dive
into a pretty intense AI fueled yeah man
era I don't I don't even for sure yeah a
lot of stuff is going to be using AI now
like you mentioned some of these
programs that are you know they've or
some of these uh companies that they I'm
already talking about as in programs
some of these companies that they that
they listed here in this article um
we'll link it in the description
um you know they've got bug Bounty
programs Quizlet snap
um instacart you know some of these
they're definitely out there
um so definitely go check those out and
see if you can hack any of the uh AI
related features because it seems like
they kind of rushed that feature out to
ride the wave so I bet there's some
sketchy stuff there 100 and I know we
had talked about in the past stuff like
prompt injection there are some ml
specific bugs uh some stuff that's
really only gonna affect chat DBT and
chat TPT and AI driven systems so those
are probably a great place to focus your
time especially right now as things are
developing yeah it's kind of a new space
like you could you could be
any of you guys could be the AI Vol guy
you know that's true are we going to
talk about bugs uh let's see uh you
wanna you wanna pick up one of these
reports here well I was gonna say
because this is reminding me like one of
my old old reports got uh got disclosed
oh really a day or two ago oh nice and
it was actually a web three bug from uh
when it says what 18.
almost five years to the date uh March
9th so all right well I wasn't planning
on talking about a bug today since we
got the other thing but you take this
and go with it man yeah so I want to
hear people thinking like you know this
is what this was like very similar kind
of timeline this is like really early on
web3 stuff was like very new and also
very new in bug bounty
um and this was just a very cool dos
that I had found uh on the RPC server
that ran this wallet so essentially you
could send a Json RPC call to This
Server
and there was a method in there to reset
the server and it was intended to be for
development use but they had it turned
on for production so
yeah yeah I totally just reset the node
oh it was funny because I didn't really
understand the impact way back then but
it's funny because I was reading through
it again and the for the triager from
their side commented it was like I
haven't verified this but it looks valid
the node is effectively oh no
upon this was this just like in the JS
files or did you like how did you how
did you get this yeah I was actually I
was looking in the source code
nice yeah yeah so the RPC server was
open source and I was just looking
through what messages
see if there was anything you know
sensitive or you know basically this
right and uh yeah sure enough you could
uh you could reset the whole RPC server
with just one call unauthenticated like
oh my gosh um yeah very cool but this is
just reminding me a lot of sort of where
we're about to be with AI right it's
we're right on the cusp of a new
technology coming in there's not a lot
of reports people are unfamiliar with it
people are unfamiliar with how to use it
in a security context and a hacking
context yeah so now is a great time to
be that person right yeah for sure it
would be really it'd be really cool they
they show in the in the article like
this curl you know that they do for the
whisper API and and for the for the chat
jpt API so I mean if you could leak you
know just to give some attack vectors
out there if you could inject into this
Json context that they're talking about
here there's a nested Json context or if
you could leak their auth Bearer to open
AP uh open AI
um maybe even if you could hit different
URLs on the api.openai.com scheme or on
that on that um domain you know via sort
of like an ssrf sort of thing that could
be really cool as well so definitely
check out those possibilities yeah and
just spitballing it also makes me wonder
about context you know there's like
conversations oh yeah how do they yeah
right so like how do they how do they
Define like this is the end of a
conversation and that could maybe open
up some risk for leaking data from a
previous conversation with a different
user or something like that I'll go to
this
go to the blog and so right where it
says the request section there's a
response Button as well right next to
python bindings and then I think there's
like a chat ID
this chat cm
uh PL ID I bet I bet it's through that
interesting very very interesting so
yeah see I would definitely
I'm gonna take a look at the API docs
yeah I'm gonna make note of it they
literally we're both making I know they
literally dumped this API like 20
minutes before we started recording so
yeah we didn't have time to dive into it
too deeply but it looks really cool
super cool but yeah so if that's
something you're interested in
definitely go check it out yeah all
right sweet that's a wrap I think for
um the first part hope you enjoy the
episode on surf it was episode two it
was the second one we reported so be
kind have mercy yeah and uh I'll
definitely try to keep that tool up
for a little while at least we'll see
how long how much you guys use it but
um yep enjoy the episode all right cool
today we are talking about a super
exciting vulnerability type I I freaking
love this this vulnerability type um
it's pretty rare it's pretty hard to
find but when you do find it it's a lot
of fun to test for and uh and it can
really result in some pretty critical
bugs so Joel you want to tell the people
about it yeah sure so um you know
headless browser ssrfs right so
a lot of times I think you'll see
different instances of this in like
different applications you might use
whether it be like
you're signing a document or you're
generating some kind of like custom PDF
or something right A lot of times these
like custom generation type things it
happens actually within like a web page
and then that web page is rendered into
a PDF and the way that it does that is
with like a headless browser so what we
mean by that is like it Chrome but like
no Chrome window right so it's like
running on the CLI it like does all the
browser stuff without actually showing a
browser window and then you can tell it
to you know you can orchestrate it to do
whatever you want beyond that so you can
have it save it as a PDF have it save it
as a PNG have it inject scripts whatever
you can you know have it do whatever you
want and that gives you a lot of
different power right right because it's
almost like you have like a client right
a user who's like doing sort of the
things that you want so if you could get
JavaScript in there your xss is going to
trigger right you don't need them to
click on anything and a lot of times
those protections are actually a lot
lower
um in those headless browsers right so
so for this specific vulnerability we've
got a couple conditions we've got we
need to find a part of the application
where they are generating some sort of
PDF or generating like a screenshot of
like a specific file and or something
like that right and then
um in in order to to get the ssrf in
order to incur the vulnerability we need
to find some way to inject HTML or uh
ideally inject uh JavaScript into that
that headless browser page right
right yeah exactly that that that that's
a little bit of a of a reach I mean it
it seems like a little bit of a of a
far-fetched uh volume type but it is out
there and I found it and you found it
and uh it as we'll see later today
Fisher has found it
um and so yeah it's definitely one to be
one to be on the lookout so
um how do we how do we go about you know
testing for this I mean are we just are
we just looking for fields that are
injected into the PDF file and then we
just kind of try to inject into those
you know as far as an xss goes likely we
normally would or how does that work
yeah so like I mentioned like a lot of
the time this happens in like PDF
generation type stuff
um I believe um the homsack actually has
um uh either a talk representation or
something about this
um so we can maybe leave a link for that
in the podcast subscription but
um yeah so a lot of times it's for like
generating a PDF and I think
um it's fine I guess to a bug Bounty
Hunter it feels like kind of like
obvious almost right but like when you
when you see it but generally it's going
to be something that like is seems to be
generated right
um you know what I mean whereas like
normally you I mean if it was just
normal HTML you could just load the HTML
right there's no reason to not give that
to the user so like they're generating
into like a document or a PDF or
something like for a reason mostly
because they want you to either download
or sign something or like they need like
a copy of it or something like that and
usually it's and a lot of times you'll
you'll actually see you know on that
note you'll see actually HTML passed
into these endpoints right like you know
you look at the the HTTP request and
they'll actually be like you know you're
less than greater than like a bold tag
or something like that in that that HTML
as a that's being passed into the the
endpoint as a parameter right
right yeah so that's a great way to test
it is just like start with HTML tags and
see if you can get like either HTML
injection or an xss
um the exercise might not be visible
because like it might not render the
alert right so like start with HTML see
if you get HTML injection just like with
like xss or anything else right if
you're fuzzing Fields so start with
those payloads if you see it like return
like a PDF for example or like an image
um with like your bold html element like
in there then that's like a great sign
that you should like start poking and
prodding at that maybe try and identify
what headless browser they're using
um like the specific version or the type
like the what piece of software it is
specifically and then you can you know
take a look at the source code take a
look at other vulnerabilities that have
affected that see if you can exploit it
nice yeah no that that makes a lot of
sense and and to your point you know we
don't actually like like normal
um xss we don't have access to the or
unlike normal exercise we don't actually
have access to like the Dom that's being
rendered right so we can't just look you
know right click view source and see
where the payload's being injected we
actually need sort of a visual visual
feedback for this right so we probably
want to try to use something that's
going to give you know like an H1 tag or
something that even might break out of
other tags that might you know where the
data might be rendered and and give us
something some sort of visual feedback
on whether we're breaking out of uh out
of a tag or out of a parameter right
yeah yeah this is one of those instances
where like having like a malformed
payload might actually be kind of useful
just because you can see like some of
the mess you know what I mean sort of
start to show up and then you'll be like
oh wait a second like this might be a
good opportunity and then then you can
like further in you know Pokemon prod
um you actually have a tool that's
relevant to this though yeah man okay
it's cool so I can talk about that a
little bit now
um yeah so essentially the whole reason
we did this episode in the first place
was because Fisher hit me up the other
day and was like Yo dude I've got this
headless browser or ssrf and it was
pretty much just exactly the scenario
that we just talked about which was
um like you know there's a there's a
parameter that's being passed into in
the end point and that parameter just
takes HTML and then just shoves it in a
headless browser and renders it
um and so obviously
um you know there's not too much to poke
around there for for xss right you can
pretty easily you know inject your HTML
tag see it in the responses that's part
of the intended functionality
and then from there you know either
using on event handlers or script tags
in our scenario the script tags work
just fine
um
to go ahead and execute JavaScript and
then try to get a callback on your
server
um so you know he hit me up he's like
man I cannot get any
anything of impact here because you know
at the end of the day an ssrf is great
but if the whole premise of ssrf is that
you're you're pivoting into an internal
Network and a lot of times when you get
an ssrf you have to prove to the triager
to the the company
um that you are able to hit an internal
asset whether it be localhost uh or um
the good old AWS metadata instance for
those of you that don't know about that
if you're if you're uh
if you're a vulnerable server is on AWS
there's this magical endpoint that all
of us hackers love
um
169.254.169.254 I'll never forget that
address
um
where you can hit hit that address and
it'll dump back the AWS creds for the
role associated with that ec2
um server
um which is just phenomenal and then you
just kind of dump those into the command
line and and just log into the AWS
account
um so that's that's phenomenal
um but you know in this scenario he was
having trouble finding exactly where we
could hit the uh you know what kind of
internal server we could hit
um wasn't much hosted on localhost
um couldn't hit any internal servers and
but here's the crazy thing it was on AWS
right so it was like it was like man we
should be able to do this but when he
dropped the
um
the AWS
URL into like an iframe or something
like that to pull the data back it was
it was not having it
um so he hit me up and I'm like all
right like what are we gonna do here we
can't our time frame was pretty short we
didn't really have a lot of time to do
any crazy DNS rebinding for those for
those of you that aren't familiar with
with DNS or binding um DNS you're
binding is a technique where
um you take a domain name and you abuse
the time to live on a DNS record uh to
rebind the uh hostname the the domain
name to a different IP address so for
example you hit it with an ssrf the
first time it resolves the the host it
resolves to you know public IP address
your server totally fine and the second
time it resolves the IP address
um it hits you know a local a local
server
um and that's that's a common technique
um so yeah so with with that you know we
didn't have but that that technique
takes time in modern browsers because uh
Chrome just sort of ignores that time to
live excuse me time to live on a DNS
record and so it just kind of adds it
just says five minutes it's got to be
five minutes and we didn't have that
long in the Headless browser before the
requested timeout
um
so we were looking around for uh these
other techniques and Joel I'm gonna hold
on I'm going to send you this link
really quickly this thing is it's funny
that you mentioned that because I know
like all the time when I'm making new
DNS records and stuff if I ever like
make a mistake and I'm like and I've
tested it once before like I it always
seems like it takes forever in Chrome
even if you're you're TTL it's the worst
because like crummy narza that does
whatever yeah whatever the heck they
want and they've got enough of the you
know browser Market where they can just
be like yeah you know what we're just
gonna screw with that and I just sent
you that link dude this is so funny if
you look at this link
um so this this guy Robert MD I'm just
gonna give him a shout out right here
he's such a badass he comments on NCC
group Singularity tool which is a DNS
rebinding tool one of the like top DNS
rebinding tool he's like dude why don't
we just um you know I just kind of I'm
reading this and I kind of get the Vibes
of like dude why are you trying to make
this so hard like why don't we just
instead of abusing the TTL on the DNS
record why don't we just have two IP
addresses for one a record and if the
first IP address fails it'll
automatically fall back to the second
record and I read this and I was like
there's no way that this works right
like that would just be too easy
um and and if as you look through this
this freaking GitHub issue everyone's
like yeah dude this isn't gonna work man
and then he just dropped like he's like
this is the POC it works and then it
just like drops a GitHub gist like a
total badass
so excuse me getting over a cold here
um
so yeah I I realized that and I was like
dang uh we gotta like check this out
um
and I recently switched uh from running
Ubuntu as my main OS to running Windows
and then using Windows substitute for
Linux
um
and so I go to check test this out and
it works
and I'm like what like are we all just
idiots and Robert MD is like the [__]
like
um and and it turns out you know this
this uh is a a type of um DNS you're
binding known as multi-a rebinding and
it only works um in Windows
which is a little bit of a bummer but
you know C'est La Vie however it works
really really well in Windows it it
rebinds super quickly
um and so let me just let me just back
up real quick and I'll I'll walk you
through the the actual attack Factor
right
yeah it's actually really interesting
that it's a Windows only thing because I
um I know like when I was learning about
like DNS back in college like that they
were teaching like you know set multiple
a records and all that kind of stuff
like they they're they always have like
fallbacks and stuff like even with DNS
there's like multiple DNS servers and
all that kind of stuff and it's kind of
interesting to like wonder how that kind
of like how the fallbacks actually work
and like where they're respected yeah I
I expect they're like Windows would be I
mean usually I would expect Windows to
be the outlier where it's not right
respecting that type of behavior and
everybody else was yeah so I think I
think it's mostly like a chrome on or
like Chrome on Windows sort of vibe or
but actually you know what it affects
other browsers too I think it affects
Firefox and and other browsers running
on I'm trying to look at let me pull up
this uh this issue again yeah he said it
he he said it works on Firefox Chrome
Firefox Chrome and Edge on windows so I
mean Edge and chrome obviously are
running pulse running chromium but it
does work on Firefox as well which makes
me think it's like a you know Windows
DNS internals sort of sort of problem
um but yeah but yeah so I mean pretty
much how it works is you've got uh
you've got this page you you load up
um and when you when you load up the
page uh it it obviously the the
computer has to resolve the DNS record
so it resolves to uh your server and
that DNS record that it resolves has two
two a records in there the first one
goes to your server the second one goes
to uh you know your private server and
when Windows loads it up um it's going
to take the priority
um that you you set it as so if if the
first one is your server and the second
one is localhost it's gonna it's gonna
respect that other other systems um
Linux and I believe Mac as well
um they will not do that they will look
and say uh they're going to prioritize
the localhost instance or or the local
IP instance
um so if you've got like you know
localhost is one of them then it'll
it'll just load localhost and it'll
never hit the attacker server I see that
actually makes sense because then if
you're like developing locally it would
hit your local server instead of using
the built-in yeah and it kind of makes
sense as well from like an internal
networking perspective like corporate
networking right so if you've got it
it'll also prioritize like a 10 dot you
know uh IP address like my networking
switch does this automatically like but
I think like this is probably to like
try and skip that step where like if I
hit my public IP from from home oh yeah
then it actually just routes internally
like it doesn't actually ever leave dang
that's pretty cool the router yeah the
router just handles it like if you look
on your web server like internally the
request will be coming from your
internal IP address not from like an
external dude I gotta work on my home
lab I feel like every time I talk to you
Joel you have like this sick home lab
set up and you're like look at this like
crazy automation I have to like run all
my lights and what is what's the name of
that like system that you had in places
yeah home assistant you had like so much
[__] hooked up to Home assistant and
yeah dude I'm assistant I'm jealous man
you know I'm running everything off of
uh you know Google Google homes and and
it works well but like I don't know it
seems like you got some crazy [__] set
up so that's pretty cool I mean I still
do a lot of it through homekit yeah all
of the sharing to home kit comes from
home assistant so all right well maybe
we'll have to do a different episode on
Joel's like super badass home automation
setup but um anyway so the DNS record it
resolves and uh it resolves to the
attacker's IP address then you know
you've got that page loaded up in the
browser you've got JavaScript on that
you've got control of that page then
pops open another iframe to the same
domain right
um this time when the browser uh tries
to reach out to your server right it's
cached right
um you the server will not respond the
server will kill itself
um and then when the browser realizes
that it's unable to access the server at
that IP it will reach out to the second
IP
um in this case localhost and load that
up now because you've got you know your
other Page open and you've got this new
page that is localhost but still
resolves to The Domain
um uh open now we can reach across the
iframes uh because it's the same origin
and uh and pull whatever content we've
got out
um so that that is the whole concept
behind
um this this rebind multi-a
uh tool or sort of technique and then I
I kind of built a built a little tool
around it
um yeah so the TTL is per record right
so what do you set the TTL for like when
you have multiple IPS is still just like
the lowest YouTuber well you know the
the TTL in this scenario it actually
isn't ever used right because Chrome
just disses you anyway this is going to
throw that away um you know normally
with with uh
you know traditional DNS refunding you'd
want to set the TTL to zero making sure
that it refreshes it every single time
but in this one it can cache it and it
still doesn't matter which is pretty
cool
um so yeah this is I guess I'll go ahead
and like make this repo not private now
um but essentially I'll be releasing
with the with this podcast
um the the tool called uh rebind multi-a
you can find it on my GitHub github.com
rebind multi-a and I was going to write
a blog post with it I'm not sure I'm
gonna write a blog post with it because
I wrote a pretty good readme on it so
um
yeah just go read the readme if you
didn't understand my uh you know
explanation here interrupted with my
admiration for Joel's home setup
um I will put a link for that down below
we'll drop that in the description
um but yeah so essentially I took a lot
of inspiration for this from uh
and another awesome tool
um by uh Brandon Dorsey who now uh or
rebuy Network have you have you you used
three by Network Rachel
I think so but um yeah so we'll we'll go
over it a little bit a little bit later
um I'm actually going to talk about it a
good bit in the in the book value tape
section but it's this concept of like
you it dynamically responds uh you know
dynamically
how am I gonna say this yeah so it you
know you can build a DNS record that
programs how it's going to respond
um yes okay I do yeah it's such a great
tool and I I'm really appreciate the
fact that he like hosted infrastructure
for it
um you know he he put it just put it on
a server and and used rebuy Network and
so rebind.network you know to do that so
um took a lot of inspiration from that
so I built a tool rebind multi a.com
um this is you know you guys can go out
there and just use this
um the concept behind this is you I mean
you still need your own VPS so you're
gonna have to go and get um
you know your VPS spun up because
obviously you've got to host your
payload um to do the theft of the data
that you need
um but the concept should be
uh you just you create a a record
um
uh when you run the rebound multi-a tool
on your VPS and it'll it'll respond with
uh a pay so it'll create a DNS server
and two HTTP servers
um the DNS server is going to handle the
whole DNS response part of the equation
and then the server will handle the uh
one HTTP server will handle loading the
malicious page and then killing itself
when uh the other when the second
request reaches it
um in order to you know make it fall
back to the other IP and then the the
last HTTP server the second HTTP server
will uh handle fetching the you know
handling the data exfiltrating the data
from the the browser so
um the the Target or the actual
um DNS record looks like something along
the lines of
127.0.0.1.target so that's that's the
Target that you're you're shooting for
and then you're gonna put your vps's IP
in here
um in the example on the readme I've got
uh one three one three dot
133.133.37 of course you know gotta be
late uh dot NS dot rebind multi a.com so
then
the authoritative name server for that
is of is um gonna default to whatever
you put in after the NS in the record um
that's going to be your VPS and then
your VPS will kind of take it from there
and do the whole
um exploitation
yeah this reminds me a lot of um I can't
remember the name of the tool but there
was a tool like very similar to this for
like redirects and like um different
like response codes and you could
basically like to like respond with like
any response code or like you can put
like
um you know do a 302 to this specific
URL or whatever and
um I think you could both do it directly
like through all through the domain as
well as through like domain and paths
um and it was like very similar to this
where you basically just like give it
like a single like domain it's meant to
look like legit ish you know like like
if you can only feed it like a domain
then you know you can sort of like you
know still get your way around that
um and yeah I really like the concept of
these kinds of tools because it makes it
really accessible to like everybody yeah
it's so much better I I didn't actually
know about that tool so I'm gonna have
to get maybe we gotta find that one yeah
I gotta try and find it it was I use it
ages ago that's awesome and so like the
way that I'm doing that right now is
just a bunch of like super Scrappy uh
you know PHP files in my website server
with all these different types of like
I've got like reader
308.php and reader307.php
um so yeah I mean that's a good I mean
that that's a good bug Bounty tip right
there is like when you're when you're
looking for
um you know when you're trying to see if
you can uh force a uh ssrf to follow
redirects definitely try all the
different redirect types right
yeah yeah I think the first time I heard
that tip I was at a live hacking event
and Mark Litchfield was like he comes up
to me he's like dude this is nuts like I
had I had this ssrf I was trying to
exploit it forever I couldn't get
anything and then I tried a 301 instead
of a 302 and it worked and I was like
are you serious like what what does the
code even look for that look like for
that on the server side like
so that's weird man
super weird
um but yeah so that's I mean that's the
that's the uh
that's the the tool so definitely enjoy
that let me know your thoughts on that
you can uh you can hit us up uh via
Twitter at ctpb podcast
um or info at critical
thinkingpodcast.io
um or you can just DM me that works too
DMS are open right
um I will say you have to use Python 3.7
uh because it it uses a library that's
in there so you might have to work some
Pi NV magic I don't know how to actually
say that
um yeah that's that's what it should be
like
um all right let's see what do we what
else do we want to talk about next Joel
what do we got on here
uh let's see so we can talk about
um do you want me to sort of go through
it or we can we can uh we can talk about
sort of the rce uh yeah let's let's talk
about some so yeah that's another
approach right so hit him with the RC
and the Headless browser sort of sort of
feel
yeah sure so this is actually something
that I use for more than just had this
browser it was like I'll use this on
like
um Hardware devices that are running
like Android or have like a chromium
instance or something like that
um a lot of the times it's a really easy
Vector to just find a POC for an rce
within uh you know either the the V8
JavaScript engine or
um chromium itself or any other like
Chrome you know web services and
anything like that
um and just like throw JavaScript POC at
it and see if it crashes
um because a lot of the times programs
will just accept that as is as well like
you don't have to like go like all you
don't have to write up binary
exploitation payload you can just be
like hey I crashed the browser with this
valid POC for you know a version newer
than this and they'll take it yeah dude
that's that's super badass man I know I
know Alex Chapman uh at a I'm trying to
not disclose too much information here
but at some point he has done something
similar to
um and it just absolutely freaking blew
my mind but he actually went the full
way and like wrote out the whole
like Shell Code and stuff like that you
know exploding like a like a type
um type confusion or something like that
in V8 is super badass super cool yeah so
I mean all that stuff is public right so
um just go to like the chromium
um disclose bugs page I think you could
just Google it but um I'm not gonna read
the aura but yeah you can definitely
just Google like Chrome I'll drop it in
the description box yeah it'll be in the
description somewhere and that you have
like a list of basically just like you
can go view the actual like bug that was
filed by like the researcher
includes the boc files it includes like
their automated bot that like retests it
automatically and all that kind of stuff
oh dang that's pretty cool yeah it's
really it's really cool so you have like
definitely a lot of visibility into like
basically like how this stuff is working
and then you can just go download it
yourself and test it locally and just
like you know try it out and see if it
works
um so yeah that's always like a really
great thing like it when you're messing
with browsers in general not even just
like headless ones but you know headless
ones too but just browsers in general
it's an old browser try and crash it try
and rce because these uh the JavaScript
engines that run
um within the browsers are like very
complicated so it's really easy for
there to be type confusions and like
lots of like minor little things that
turn into big bugs that happen all the
time within the JavaScript engine and
that's like a perfect exploit path
because it's JavaScript right if you can
run JavaScript then you have an exploit
path right so that's like always a
really good Vector awesome yeah I know
that that makes a lot of sense and I
feel like that is an attack Vector
that's a little bit
um
separated from the bug Bounty Community
mostly right because like I mean
obviously there's bug Bonnie for
chromium but like browser exploitation
as far as like actually exploiting the
browser as an executable as a as a piece
as a program is not something that we
talk about very much in bug Bounty
because a lot of the time we're thinking
about the attack vectors for web
applications
um you know attacking web servers or if
we are attacking the browser you know
using that to leak information about a
current user authenticated on the site
or something like that so definitely
definitely a cool piece of uh of attack
attack scope there
yeah I think you'll find that like V8
and JavaScript it's one of those
um like JavaScript engines and stuff
it's like one of those fields where like
generally the people who are like
finding a lot of the bugs and like doing
a lot of like the really cool research
are people who've been doing it for like
a long time and are like already super
familiar with like this weird complex
system that like is the JavaScript
engine and so like when you're coming
into it new like there was a point in
time where I was doing a lot of research
around like JavaScript engines and that
kind of stuff and like there's just so
much knowledge that you have like you
have to like catch up on when you're
like jumping into that because like
they're just like it's a mess of code
it's like a huge code base and you just
have to like try and sort out like oh
how does like VAR I equals zero like
what is that like that gets like handled
by like seed basically you know like
it's like yeah so it's it's very
abstract it's it's really cool though if
you ever have time it's a little
intimidating to to start off researching
to be perfectly honest like I've
definitely wanted to go down that path
before especially because like you said
it helps you pop iot devices too you
know if you've got an iot device that's
like a couple patch Cycles behind or
something like that it can be really
helpful to like just pop the browser and
then get rce on it and dump the firmware
or whatever
um but yeah pretty pretty pretty scary
but it is doable I mean we've seen
people do it you know
um
so every year at Pondo yeah exactly
right
um well cool so that's that's the RC
inside of the Headless browser um so
that's that's another approach you could
take so bringing it all back around
you've got your headless browser if you
see a headless browser if you see like a
PDF generator or something like that in
your um in your scope definitely you
know poke around at it quite a bit
because there's a lot of attack vectors
you can go with for that and I'm
actually going to jump back a little bit
to talk about headless browser
um exploitation a little bit more in
depth here like you mentioned nahomsek
has a really awesome talk I want to say
it was in 2019 about
um essentially how to get lfi through
headless browsers and there's some crazy
stuff in there
um about uh like using a link tag to
embed a file in in the rendering or of
that PDF that happens and it's like
dang why does this even work but it did
um and I think a lot of this stuff is
dependent on the on the you know on the
software that's being used to render
this right
right and that's why I like recommended
like if you can like poke around a
little bit and try and like identify
like start with just like you know HTML
and like those types of things just your
basic like fuzzing of fields and see
what type of output you get and then
like start searching for like the
abnormalities and see if you can get a
hit like on a GitHub issue or somebody
like you know posting something that
mentions what software oh I'm
experiencing this weird issue with this
software like you know that happens all
the time where somebody's like
legitimately trying to use it and they
like encounter the same kind of problem
go read the GitHub issues man that's the
takeaway from the days like you might
find the next Robert MD who's just like
this is stupid
go read the get up issues exactly yeah
and if you look at the other one that I
had here uh Joel was like this this
right up by Jonathan Bowman who's a
stellar hacker love love working with
him at live hacking events
um and essentially he
he and this is another shout out to the
specific you know go and figure out
exactly what is rendering your your PDF
you know in this scenario it was mpdf uh
you know a specific library and as he
was reading through the docs for this he
found a way to
um include a specific file in it with
you know with an annotation tag and you
know you're probably not going to have
success doing exactly this but it's
important for you to look it's important
for us all to look at the methodology
here and say like you know how far he
went down that path right
yeah yeah exactly it's it's definitely
you know not as sexy sometimes to go in
there and read the documentation and
like just get super deep in that sort of
thing but you really see some crazy
bones pop out of that
well that was the other thing I was
going to mention when we were talking
about like all the weird DNS behavior is
like I think like a lot of these complex
systems like one big takeaway is like
there's almost always like a
documentation related bug where like
there's something that is like literally
documented as expected behavior and it's
not not okay it's not right exactly not
okay exactly like it's like bad behavior
that is intended and they've just been
like yeah this is how this is supposed
to work but when you come at it from the
attacker's mindset then you like you
know you can use that in malicious ways
whether it be like oh we're just
rendering this page we give it an image
URL and it puts it in the page it's like
yeah but you can give it any URL right
something like that right so
um just go read the docs right read the
docs read the issues like figure out
people are like using this and just like
you'll definitely find something like
strange in there that to look absolutely
yeah no I I definitely think that's such
a valuable you know it I I dumped that
tip on almost every one of those like
give me a random bug Bounty tip you know
Twitter just like read the freaking docs
and I think I think NT I actually didn't
get the chance to see it but NC I think
did a uh a talk recently on like just go
read the freaking RFC and that has
literally never not paid off for me I'm
sitting down and reading the RFC so
that's another
another fire fire one there
yeah for sure um the only other thing
Joe that I had in this uh you know
section about headless uh browser ssrf
sort of exploitation was this piece on
uh and this is kind of sort of like a
last resort right we don't really want
to resort to this but at the end of the
day they will still give you a medium on
an ssrf if you can do internal Port
scanning with it most of the time
um and there is this cool tool by
some guy named
avilium I'm sorry I found I didn't
pronounced that correctly but that's
what it is and uh it's actually a uh web
um
webassembly Port scanner
um that you can just run in your browser
and I you know before we ran this I or
before we did this podcast I tried to
spin this up and try to get it to work
and I couldn't get it to work and I I
you know put it put an issue out there
and he's like yeah dude it works
and and so I was like okay all right and
it very well could be like some weird
networking that's happening with WSL
um that definitely does happen but he
swears up and down that it works and it
seems pretty badass so definitely
something to check out if you're in a
situation where you can uh you know
where you need to prove internal Port
scanning or something like
yeah webassembly is one of those things
that I think is like it's like a secret
hidden little you know that's gonna come
get really soon you know what I mean
because like I think that not a lot of
people are really looking at that yeah
and like there's a lot of stuff that
seems kind of like
why I mean I've seen like people like
you compile doom and like run it in the
browser and stuff like that you know
what I mean so it's like the levels the
levels are pretty like we're I think
we're already like there people just
need to like figure out yeah and this
seems like a good use and to your
previous point you know this uh
webassembly is something that's used
fairly often I think in in exploitation
of uh those RCS that we were talking
about earlier you know you've got to
have a pretty good grip on that
um which is once again just another
another Arena of Deep dive you need to
do to be able to fully exploit these
things but I do think it would be really
interesting to to and I want to say like
I bookmarked if I find it you know
before we release the show I'll drop it
in the show notes but I want to say I I
bookmarked a uh
a talk that someone did or maybe like a
a uh blog post that someone did not too
long ago about like how to get into
browser bugs for noobs essentially
yeah that is a really I actually do have
some things bookmarked here I'll send
you some links yeah do treat them over
and actually yeah I found it actually
Jack Allen
um he says today I'm releasing a uh
three-part browser exploitation series
on Chrome and I started looking into
this dude and it's really interesting
stuff he writes up highly recommend
um checking out his blog so I'll drop
this I'll drop this in the uh in the
description as well for the for the
episode but um awesome yeah just getting
a cursory understanding of what all that
looks like I think would be really
helpful even for web Hunters because you
do run into these situations where
you're hitting an iot device or you're
you know hitting in a headless browser
where this could be really helpful
yeah for sure
dude and make sure that as well actually
yeah yeah I want to give that a reason
I'm dropping in the chat right now
um all right sorry for the for the
coughing in the mic
just dude this cold has held on for so
freaking long man like it's been so
annoying it's that time of year you know
yeah for sure
um all right I think that's all we had
on content for headless browser ssrfs
I'm trying to think if there's anything
else not that not that I can come up
with off the top of my head
um so yeah now it's time for everybody's
favorite segment which is like random
bug Bounty tips slash interesting stuff
to talk about
um so yeah I guess I'll I'll go ahead
and start us off with the one with the
cool one from Lupine yeah does that work
yeah yeah go for it okay so
I want to say
I want to say it was Vegas that I talked
to Lupine about this over like pancakes
at the what is the name of that the
hotel in Vegas with like the the giant
pyramid
yeah that was it we were in the Luxor
and we were at like this breakfast place
and we're just sitting down and talking
about like headless browser ssrf and
like stuff as we do
um and he dropped this fire tip which I
ended up using in a headless browser
ssrf exploitation
um not too long ago
which was
um you know a lot of times in these sort
of scenarios you have a certain time
frame where you have to uh get your
payload off you know in like three
seconds or something or the HTTP request
times out or something like that right
and so of course you know in those
scenarios first thing that comes to your
head is like okay well I'll just stall
the HTTP response right you know I'll
just write a little PHP code you know
return sleep or whatever and and then
just you know return an empty file or
whatever on an image tag
um and that works fine and will probably
buy you like couple seconds or whatever
but there's a different timeout he told
me on
um loading the body of HTTP responses
um and so if you go ahead and you
respond with the headers
um you know the 200 response and you
give it a Content length of one and then
you don't respond with anything else it
there's a different timeout value on how
long it will wait for uh the body of
that HTTP response to be kicked back
versus uh you know the actual just HTTP
response itself which I thought was
really interesting
um yeah that's actually really that's a
really good tip um because if you think
about like
like you mentioned there's like
different timeouts like along the way
there's like the connection timeout
there's like the HTTP time right there's
like you know all different timeouts
like at different places and they might
not actually be defined the same way and
also they start at different points yeah
so that's a good point actually I wonder
if it would be most efficient to try to
like optimize all of those timeouts and
say something like okay we're going to
stall the TCP connection for like you
know if the limit's three seconds like
2.9 seconds as you can yeah and then and
then do that at each step along the way
install the HTTP response for like five
seconds stall the HTTP response body for
like you know however long
um but yeah so if you ever need to buy
yourself some extra time in it in that
sort of headless browser context you can
definitely use that
um yeah just empty body content length
one exactly and then you know you'll do
whatever your whatever else you know
you're doing in JavaScript on a
different part of the page so that's
that's a pretty cool one I think it
bought me like 15 seconds uh it went
from like 1.5 seconds to 15 seconds when
I tried it
um so that's pretty badass
yeah that's really cool um another one
is like um Chrome is like super like
good at talking to other like Chrome
instances you know what I mean like
chromium and all those kinds of things
so like
um there's a there's a thing called
Chrome inspect
um Chrome slash inspect and this plays
with like a lot of other things like um
the remote debugging stuff and I'll let
you talk about that in a sec but like
with the inspect page you can like
um for example if you have an Android
device and you have a web view on that
Android device you plug it in to your
computer you open Chrome inspect you can
interact with the JavaScript console on
that page on the device
like over USB from your computer and you
can like you know inspect element you
can look through the HTML you can do all
that kind of stuff if your phone's in
debug mode so
um that's like a really really useful
tool if you're trying to like debug like
oh what does this page have access to or
like uh what is where where is my code
like being rendered on this webview or
whatever you know like you can take a
little closer look if you just plug your
phone dude that would be hella helpful
for like trying to enumerate those
um like special JS handlers that you
have sometimes in like mobile app web
views or something like that I don't
know if it works I use it to build my
payload all the time actually oh really
like what yeah yeah because it's just
way easier like you just open up the
page you don't have to like get your
whole Facebook
start testing your payload until it does
what you want and then you just figure
out how to inject that payload dang I
gotta I gotta test that out sometimes I
wish I I've been working on
um I don't know I guess I'll say just a
certain iot device and I freaking cannot
get this thing to get into debug mode
where I can get any sort of like access
to the JavaScript console on it so I I
also think it would be really cool I
don't know if this tool is out there I'm
sure it does with like some of the OG I
want to say there was a tool that like
would drop a JavaScript shell back to
you but I think it'd be so helpful to
just be able to load up a page right and
then like have another page that it
connects to maybe via like websockets or
even like just command line thing where
you could just run interactive
JavaScript when you don't have access to
the inspect console
and you're reminding me I saw a tweet
there's something about that I feel like
there was yeah I saw a tweet like
yesterday oh yeah here we go broadcast
channel I'm gonna send this to you on on
what is what broadcast channel
yeah I think this is a new JavaScript
API
oh dang that sounds that sounds uh but
it's like across it's cross window like
crosstab like okay that's my jam right
now so definitely send that to me I I've
been studying recently like all the
different ways you can uh you know reach
across various JavaScript you know reach
like into the iframe you can do it via
post messages you can do all sorts of
crazy stuff what the heck
I know right
dude you're just dropping me on this
dropping this on me in the middle of a
podcast like what the heck I know I saw
that this morning okay dude we gotta
wrap this up and go read this
um all right that's fire so we'll leave
that in the we'll leave that in the the
description as well I wonder if this can
be used for I wonder if this is specific
use cases or if this can actually just
broadcast to
uh if you can because really one of the
problems that I've been trying to solve
is like how do I get explain and this is
especially relevant in this modern day
of like uh you know same site cookies
and and that sort of thing where you
have to do top level navigation how do I
get access to a tab that I didn't open
um to send it like a post message or
something like that because if I could
do that it would be really helpful for a
lot of bugs so this actually looks super
promising I'm definitely going to check
this out
yeah yeah and I wonder if you just have
to like open that Channel or if you
could like brute force it or maybe if
there's a default Channel yeah dude some
probably some interesting things to look
into yeah no there's definitely going to
be bones here right because it says it
looks like in I'm just you know looking
at a cursory
lens at it but it looks like they just
you know Define a static broadcast
channel so if you have a static you know
if it's not something that's being
dynamically generated you can just send
messages into that
um yeah yeah it looks like it I
definitely gotta mess with this okay oh
Julian I just pulled up the mdn on it
it's it's supported across all of
all of the browsers already
dude all right we're gonna we're gonna
poke it back all right extra that was an
extra Buck Bounty tip for you today
don't you know don't snipe our bugs
don't go find all the bugs in that uh
before we do
um obviously who now that you mentioned
yeah so by Brandon doors or Brandon
Dorsey that's like a great tool for DNS
rebinding it's just like all in the
domain record itself you just like chain
it all together with dots and you have
like one big like subdomain chain that
explains like how your DNS rewind Works
super useful who now that one's crazy
useful I use this one all the time
um it's so nice that he just hosted it
and like you don't have to worry about
it but I did at some point
um because I need to do some
modifications to it I did uh spin up my
own one my own you know version of who
now and it's super easy to do so don't
let that intimidate you either
um you know I hadn't worked a lot with
uh DNS protocol before screwing around
with this and and one of the tools I'll
mention in just a second
um and so definitely don't shy away from
that it'll it'll help you grow and it's
actually not not super tricky
yeah um so yeah I guess I'll keep it on
that same vein the next one that I had
here that I wanted to drop as a as a tip
was DNS chef and actually Mr Tux racer
shout out to Julian there
um gave me showed me this a while back
um but this is a great way and this is
helpful in so many contexts it's helpful
and I yeah I just opened this up and I
already had the repost yeah I did it
nice yeah I I um I used this all the
time for creating fake uh DNS records
um and and sort of proxying through and
it's really great because like for
example if you can set your router to
have a default DNS and then push that to
an iot device right when it connects to
your router then
um when that you can snipe specific uh
DNS records right so it you know set
your VPS as the default DNS server
and then it'll proxy every record that's
not the specific record that you talk
about to like 8.88 or something like
that and then it will allow you to
override a specific record which can
allow you to inject yourself into some
pretty baller situations when you're
writing exploits so that's pretty cool
yeah I do a similar thing then I know
we've talked about this with iot devices
where
um you can force a a webview to pop up
with captive portals right captive
portals you go to Starbucks you connect
to their Wi-Fi you got to check the box
right the little thing that pops up you
got to check the box and agree and click
agree right before you get internet
access well that's called The Captive
portal right and so like most devices
support that like it's part of normal
like inner like Wi-Fi stuff right so
like on an iot device you just give it
your own capture portal you force it to
open the captive portal and it will open
a webview that you can run JavaScript in
and you can you know it's like yeah
freaking Joel is like dropping all of
these bug Bounty tips that are not in
our notes and I'm like dude like I sit
here and I like script out my notes I
was like oh I'll drop this tip for that
tip and then Joel has like literally no
notes here and just like drops these
fire yeah
definitely check that out definitely
helpful Joel told me about that
technique a while back and I used it on
an iot device and it worked quite well
so definitely don't forget that one and
I dude I think that's such a valuable I
think that's such a valuable piece about
cyber security content like this right
because it's like you know if you just
like that's pretty creative you know the
the captive portal and if you just kind
of get that in your head as a possible
attack vector as a possible
um you know beginning of an attack or
something like that you never know when
that's going to pop up and when you're
going to use it and how it's going to
make you grow as an attacker to think
like that so I love that
all right
um oh yeah so you kind of touched on dev
Chrome uh uh Chrome devtools protocol a
little bit but I actually wanted to talk
this out
this is not necessarily a bug Bounty tip
more of it's like please go hack this
everybody who listens to this podcast
because it seems really like an
interesting scope
so I was looking at this and I feel like
um this is something that I have not
tried very much in the context of uh
headless browser situations because I'd
imagine this Dev tools protocol is open
on a lot of these headless browsers
because there's got to be some way for
them to orchestrate that headless
browser right
um so definitely check out devtools
protocol there's a when you instantiate
headless Chrome there's a remote or dash
dash remote debugging Port
um parameter that you can put into
enable remote debugging on on the
chromium instance and it opens up some
really interesting endpoints
um obviously there's one that I'm about
to highlight is kind of like a
semi-vulnerability that I found but it's
not really a vulnerability and what it
is is you know how like browsers have a
limitation on unlike pop-ups and you
can't like pop up like you know eight
digibillion tabs uh you know with one
root if you hit if you uh open up remote
debugging port and you hit slash
localhost Json new and you give it as a
as a query parameter you give it a URL
it will open up a tab
and then it will open up another tab
with that URL you defined right and so
you can pop up two tabs with and one
that you control and one that has a
parent or an opener relationship
um with this slash Json new and so that
allows you to circumvent some of the
pop-up stuff which I think is pretty
cool um and then there's you know
obviously the chromium code is open open
source so you can go read through it and
I was just looking at the way that it
handles HTTP requests and such looks
like there's a really ripe
um attack surface there so definitely if
anyone's feeling up to it go poke at
that could provide some some cool attack
surface and I was just kind of perusing
through the chromium disclosed bugs like
you mentioned before Joel and they do
pay for bugs in that
um so I mean you'll get a universal
exercise that would be sick dude that'd
be so cool and the other thing is if you
can leak you know if you can figure out
how to leak the
um good for these inspect so because you
know what it's talking about the purpose
of this is to be able to do remote kind
of like what you're talking about before
July I imagine that's exactly the same
thing actually if you open the Chrome
inspect Tab and you look at like there's
actually a button in there that says
like um
it says like discover Network targets
and if you click configure it shows like
you know localhost Port 9222 9229 right
so there's like a default set in there
for
um like picking up those remote
debugging instances and it's the exact
same thing it's just that with Android
you put your phone on debug mode and you
plug it in over USB it'll do all the the
same things as it would with a remote
Target
wow okay yeah I'm looking at that now
that's okay that makes so much sense so
you know then then you have that remote
debugging
um accessible and if you can get the
Guide the correct URL for that then you
can control that page and you can run
arbitrary JavaScript on that page which
would result in in universal access
really cool attack surface there
definitely check it out if anybody's
into
um sort of Fringe browser uh
exploitation because for me you know as
a web hacker getting into all that V8
stuff and and a lot of dealing with a
lot of
um you know stuff I'm not familiar with
a little intimidating but dealing with a
you know localhost API is a lot less
scary so I think I'm going to dig around
a little bit there and I hope you guys
go in and find something interesting
there as well
you know some good research for sure
awesome all right man I think that's a
wrap I don't know you got anything else
you want to mention on this episode I
think that's it for now all right sweet
awesome well thanks everyone for
listening and uh yeah we'll we'll see
you next time yeah peace